[SPEAKER_02]: four months later.
[SPEAKER_02]: Let me describe myself so you know what kind of a person you're talking with here.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm 55 years old.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm about five foot seven.
[SPEAKER_02]: I weigh about 150 pounds and I'm losing my hair.
[SPEAKER_02]: Getting bald-headed?
[SPEAKER_03]: That's natural.
[SPEAKER_02]: My forehead is getting bigger all the time and I never
[SPEAKER_02]: was anything of an athlete myself, but I followed him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I envied those who had the talent and skills, and I just wished I could have been able to do something.
[SPEAKER_02]: I could have played baseball, but I couldn't hit or run or throw or field, so instead of that I was... Hit, throw, or field.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I have here in my hand a Xerox page from a
[SPEAKER_02]: baseball book published in 1933 called Who's Who in Major League Baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: Johnson?
[SPEAKER_03]: Pete Johnson.
[SPEAKER_03]: I remember where the picture was made, right there at the old Del Prado Hotel.
[SPEAKER_03]: In Chicago, was it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_02]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, so it shows your record up through 1932 and gives a little bit of history here.
[SPEAKER_03]: As long as I was with Washington, went to the White Sox.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, it has your first year of the White Sox in 1932.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's written, but this particular article is written by Ralph Cannon of the Chicago Daily News.
[SPEAKER_02]: Roy Muyiwe, good man.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_02]: Let me read it.
[SPEAKER_02]: You probably know this pretty well, but let me read it over, and then maybe suggest some things.
[SPEAKER_02]: It says, the ideal big league second baseman is a long-legged fellow who knows how to keep his feet apart in a double play so he wouldn't get knocked off his pins by an on-charging base runner.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Jack Hayes, young Chicago Sox, White Sox second sacker,
[SPEAKER_02]: who was picked out of the Southern colleges while hobbling around with a twisted knee, fulfills that designation.
[SPEAKER_02]: And according to manager Joe Cronin of Washington, who played next to him for several years as the best double play man in the American League.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Hayes was bid for twice by scout Joe Engel of Washington before he signed.
[SPEAKER_02]: Jack was having a good year at shortstop his sophomore year at the University of Alabama, hitting around 400, when one night, after they had played Georgia Tech in Atlanta,
[SPEAKER_02]: Wallace Wade, the Alabama coach, called Jack in his room and said that a big league scout, Joe Engel of Washington, wanted him to quit school and sign a contract with the Senators.
[SPEAKER_02]: Can you talk a little bit about that experience, as you recall it?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, I refused to.
[SPEAKER_03]: I told him I wouldn't do it until I talked with my father.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, you wanted me to be a doctor.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I was in school, and I talked with him, and finally I decided Washington was working with Birmingham.
[SPEAKER_03]: I decided to sign with Birmingham.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I signed with Birmingham and joined them in June.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I didn't play in a ball game.
[SPEAKER_03]: This is 1927, right?
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I was with them until July.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, this is odd, the way it happened.
[SPEAKER_03]: The manager, you remember Johnny Dobbs.
[SPEAKER_03]: You've heard of him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I know he's a Southern League manager.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was out on the infield catching some ground balls and just flipping them over to first.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know how you do it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I came up to him.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, Jack, can you throw a van?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, sure, I'll throw a van.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, Mr. Griffith, the owner of the Wiesenball Club, Mr. Joe Engle is Chief Scout up in the stand.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's before the ball game started.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, they want you to throw overhands.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, why?
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, they just purchased your contract.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, what you talking about?
[SPEAKER_03]: Are you kidding me?
[SPEAKER_03]: I've never played a ball game.
[SPEAKER_03]: How do they know?
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, I don't know, but they've just purchased your contract.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, when can you be ready?
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, are you kidding me?
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd never played a professional ball game.
[SPEAKER_03]: See, I said, are you kidding?
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, no.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, when can you be ready?
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, I can be ready right now.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, no, you're going out of home state two days.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was on Thursday, Friday, and Saturday.
[SPEAKER_03]: I came, said, you leave here Sunday morning and report to Washington.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't go up there Sunday morning to catch the train.
[SPEAKER_03]: I went Saturday night to be sure.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I wouldn't miss the train.
[SPEAKER_03]: And when I got into Washington, I walked in the clubhouse, and there was Goose Garland, Walter Johnson, Bucky Harris.
[SPEAKER_03]: Joe Judge, you know the little strips across over the locker?
[SPEAKER_03]: Walter Johnson and all of them, Joe Judge and Garland Braxton, Fred Marbury, Benny Tate, Muddy Rule, you know all those ballplayers, Goose Gosling.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, man, this big league is the place for me.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the first thing that popped my mind, this big league's the place for me to play.
[SPEAKER_03]: I want to stay up here.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I was with them five years, and Walter, when Johnson took over, he traded Bump Hadley.
[SPEAKER_03]: and Sam Jones and myself to Chicago.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, Sam Jones lived just about 25 miles from where I am now.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, he was my old roommate.
[SPEAKER_02]: One of the finest fellows.
[SPEAKER_02]: Woodsville?
[SPEAKER_03]: I went up to Woodsville.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've been in Woodsville.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: And went down to, what's that place in Virginia?
[SPEAKER_03]: Wheeling, where they played the exhibition game.
[SPEAKER_03]: We went up there one time, barnstormed, Sam and I. Oh, that was years ago.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, tell me about your earlier years.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, you were born here in Clanton, right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_02]: Lived here all my life.
[SPEAKER_02]: And your father was a doctor here?
[SPEAKER_02]: And how did you happen to go, did you play ball in high school and so on?
[SPEAKER_03]: Played ball all my life.
[SPEAKER_02]: High school, grammar school, high school.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you begin playing with rocks and broken bats and things like that or did you have pretty...
[SPEAKER_03]: There used to be a corn shelling machine down here in the gym below my house, way down where I used to live.
[SPEAKER_03]: There was a lot of corn cobs down there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Back then I played with two little colored boys.
[SPEAKER_03]: They'd throw to me and we had corn cobs and Broomhound was a bat.
[SPEAKER_03]: If you could hear the corn cob coming up that way you could fly in 50 pieces.
[SPEAKER_03]: If you caught one piece, you're out.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that's the way we started.
[SPEAKER_03]: Sit down, Angel.
[SPEAKER_02]: Okay, they had a high school here in Clanton?
[SPEAKER_02]: What's the county name?
[SPEAKER_02]: Chilton County, high school.
[SPEAKER_03]: I made a letter in all sports.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: I got the Alabama plaque.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they gave me a plaque when I was inducted into the Alabama Sports Hall of Fame this year.
[SPEAKER_02]: I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did you play in football?
[SPEAKER_02]: What positions?
[SPEAKER_02]: Quarterback.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_02]: And basketball?
[SPEAKER_02]: Played forward.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you pretty full grown in high school?
[SPEAKER_03]: I was a little fellow.
[SPEAKER_03]: Weighed 99 pounds.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that coming over?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Weighed 99 pounds.
[SPEAKER_03]: Playing football?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, sir, and they'd reach up on the first game.
[SPEAKER_03]: I remember the first game I played in.
[SPEAKER_03]: You can see these big boys and they'd just catch me by the belt, throw me down like a wet dish rag, flop me down on the ground.
[SPEAKER_03]: The manager would take me out and put somebody else in though.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, Jack said, you're my kicker.
[SPEAKER_03]: So we was playing a high school team by Tallison.
[SPEAKER_03]: I always remember this in my football days.
[SPEAKER_03]: But the game was tied.
[SPEAKER_03]: last quarter, he said, Jack, you go in, and back then they drop kicked.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, you drop kick that ball through the goal.
[SPEAKER_03]: He didn't say, see if you can.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, you do it.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I went in there and drop kicked the ball, and I went through the goal, and we beat them 10 to 7.
[SPEAKER_03]: The next day, we had chapel exercise in school back then, and the professor was Mr. Stevenson.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, Jack Hayes, you come up here a minute.
[SPEAKER_03]: I walked up on the stage.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't know what in the world he was up to, all those kids out there.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, well, boys and girls, I want you to meet the man with the educated toe.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I was known as the man with the educated toe.
[SPEAKER_02]: When did you begin to grow and add on some weight and so on?
[SPEAKER_02]: I weighed about 150 when I went to the university.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was in 1922.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did you happen to go to the University of Alabama then?
[SPEAKER_03]: Always was an Alabama fan.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that was one reason.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I knew they had good coaching over there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wanted good coaching.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Coach Wade was not only a great football coach, but he was a good baseball coach.
[SPEAKER_03]: He coached both sports together.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wallace Wade.
[SPEAKER_02]: Wallace Wade is right.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the man.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you were in there after the Joey Sewell and his crowd.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, Joey and them went in in 19 and 20 and along in there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was there later.
[SPEAKER_03]: I followed Joe and Luke and Stevenson.
[SPEAKER_03]: They were all ahead of me.
[SPEAKER_03]: They were all on the same baseball team over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Wasn't that Sun Baseball?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: They had a great ball club.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was the coach over there when you played baseball at Alabama?
[SPEAKER_03]: At Alabama?
[SPEAKER_02]: Coach Wallace Wade.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, that's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who's the Zen Scott they talk about?
[SPEAKER_02]: That was before my time, way before.
[SPEAKER_02]: Wade came after him.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: OK, did you go finish up at Alabama to graduate?
[SPEAKER_03]: I quituated.
[SPEAKER_03]: Two years, two years.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I tell you, I was taking medicine in the lab.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I could hear that baseball hitting the bat out there in the spring.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I told my daddy, I said, I don't want to be a doctor.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, well, what do you want to do?
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, I want to be a baseball player.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, well, as bad as I hate to see you do that, I've always wanted somebody to follow me.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wanted you to be a doctor.
[SPEAKER_03]: But if you want baseball, it's up to you.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I took up baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Quite agreeable to it, then, although he would have perhaps preferred you stayed in medicine.
[SPEAKER_03]: Right, right.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said later he would, but after I got into baseball, he loved baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: He always liked baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I've always spent all my winters in my hometown.
[SPEAKER_03]: When baseball season was over, I couldn't wait to get back to Clampton.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you get homesick, though, when you were away?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: We had too much fun.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had too much fun to get homesick.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had one of the greatest baseball pitches in baseball as a roommate, Ted Lyons.
[SPEAKER_03]: You remember Ted?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was my roommate for years, until I married.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he was a great guy.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I got a hit the first time I went to bat.
[SPEAKER_03]: This was now in Washington?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_03]: And who do you think we were playing?
[SPEAKER_03]: White Sox?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who do you think was pitching?
[SPEAKER_02]: Ted Lyons.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ted Lyons.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I went over to that club when I was traded over there and he was my roommate, one of the best friends.
[SPEAKER_03]: baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: I want to tell you though something about one of the, I guess you might call it the oddest baseball game that I ever played in.
[SPEAKER_03]: Washington, we were playing the White Sox.
[SPEAKER_03]: Seemed like all of it happened to the White Sox.
[SPEAKER_03]: We were against the White Sox.
[SPEAKER_03]: Going into the ninth inning, Joe Judge came to bat and hit a triple.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, Stuffy Stewart was a faster man, score was tied.
[SPEAKER_03]: They sent Stuffy in there to come in.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that a player?
[SPEAKER_02]: Walter Stewart?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, Stuffy Stewart.
[SPEAKER_03]: Fast man.
[SPEAKER_03]: Put him on third and he scored.
[SPEAKER_03]: And we all thought the ball game was over in the clubhouse undressed.
[SPEAKER_03]: Umpires came and said, that ball game isn't over.
[SPEAKER_03]: Willie Cam got the ball, stepped on third base, said Stewart left third too soon.
[SPEAKER_03]: So we had to go back, took about an hour to get all the people back in the stand, get the players in the place.
[SPEAKER_03]: They threw a ball to Aussie Bluejee and he hit a double.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I came up right after Bluejee and hit a single and we scored the win and run.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now that was an odd baseball game.
[SPEAKER_03]: The oddest thing that I ever saw happen in a ball game, I believe, was we were playing, now I'm not sure about this, but I think it was a Mother's Day.
[SPEAKER_03]: Mrs. Bob Feller, Bob's mother, rather, it was Bob's mother, was sitting behind the White Sox screen, where the big screen is there just below it.
[SPEAKER_03]: He either fouled the ball or he pitched the ball and fouled it off.
[SPEAKER_03]: Out of 40,000 people in the stand, the ball hit her in the face and broke her nose and broke her glasses.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, that's the oddest thing I saw.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I saw Babe Ruth hit his, what was it, 60th home run or 70th?
[SPEAKER_03]: 60th, off of Tom Zachary, my old roommate.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's in 1927.
[SPEAKER_03]: 1927 in Yankee Stadium.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you joined
[SPEAKER_02]: How long were you with Washington that year, 27?
[SPEAKER_02]: Five years.
[SPEAKER_02]: The first year you went up.
[SPEAKER_02]: I went up in July.
[SPEAKER_02]: They sold me in July.
[SPEAKER_02]: And who was there?
[SPEAKER_02]: You played second base right away?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, no, no.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was utility in field.
[SPEAKER_03]: I played four positions.
[SPEAKER_03]: Back now, they have I don't know how many utilities.
[SPEAKER_03]: Back then, they only had one.
[SPEAKER_03]: One year, I played third base, shortstop, second base, and first base.
[SPEAKER_03]: All around, when they get crippled, they'd holler for me to come in.
[SPEAKER_03]: In the first game I played in, strange as it was, Booker Harris looked up and down the bench and said, Jack said, you go in third base.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd never played third base.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, you go in third base and relieve Bluejee.
[SPEAKER_03]: If he'd have said, you go and catch, I'd have put the mask on and tried it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I loved it that much.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was Peckinpah still on the team?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: A year or two before he left.
[SPEAKER_02]: Why was your name Jack?
[SPEAKER_02]: Nickname?
[SPEAKER_03]: Like a man, Mr. Griffith came through here one time in the fall, and one of our city policemen, all dressed in his uniform, he stopped and said, do you know where I can find Mentor Hayes?
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, who?
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, Mentor Hayes.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, no, we have a Dr. Hayes, we have a Dick Hayes, we have an Ellick Hayes, and we have a Jack Hayes here.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, there he is, standing on the corner right over there.
[SPEAKER_03]: So Mr. Griffith always knew me as Mentor, see, and asked for Mentor, and he said Jack.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was it.
[SPEAKER_02]: They know you as Jack as a boy?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: Nickname all the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is the Mentor a family name?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, it's just a name that my father gave me.
[SPEAKER_02]: Carney, is that a family name?
[SPEAKER_03]: Carney, that's a drug salesman's name, they say it.
[SPEAKER_03]: One of my dad's drugs seven years ago.
[SPEAKER_03]: My dad used to, back then they made their own medicine, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: And you wouldn't wash bottles.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's why I'd pick up a nickel once in a while.
[SPEAKER_03]: Go up there and wash out the bottles, and they'd send them back.
[SPEAKER_02]: OK. Bucky Harris still playing at second base then?
[SPEAKER_03]: When I was there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then Buddy Meyer came along right after I left, I think, from Boston.
[SPEAKER_02]: In 1928, it says here, you played 60 games.
[SPEAKER_02]: 28, yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then you went to Minneapolis.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I was just for training for second base.
[SPEAKER_03]: Went over there two months in 1928.
[SPEAKER_03]: Went over there for two months.
[SPEAKER_02]: So they sent you down to Minneapolis to learn how to?
[SPEAKER_03]: Just for two months.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they told me I wanted to be a second baseman.
[SPEAKER_03]: I trained for second base.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: When I came back, Bucky was getting old, a replacement.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then the next year, in 2031, Walter Johnson traded me to the Chicago White Sox.
[SPEAKER_02]: How'd you like Bucky Harris as a manager?
[SPEAKER_03]: Great.
[SPEAKER_03]: One of the best I've had.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think Bucky Harris,
[SPEAKER_03]: Jimmy Dykes understood men more than any of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: But Fonseca was sharp.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, he knew his stuff.
[SPEAKER_03]: But Walter Johnson, now, I hate to talk about anybody.
[SPEAKER_03]: He could throw that ball by him.
[SPEAKER_03]: He thought his pitches should go out and throw it by him.
[SPEAKER_03]: But the faster they threw it, the harder they hit it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't think so much of him as a manager, but as a man, he was great.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a fine fellow.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was talking to Rick Stevenson and Joey Stewart yesterday.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we were talking about the matter of great players as managers.
[SPEAKER_02]: It seemed like the better the player was, the poorer the manager he was.
[SPEAKER_02]: The great managers are often mediocre players.
[SPEAKER_02]: They expect it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, MacArthur never did play, did he?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Very little in the big time.
[SPEAKER_02]: But people like Cobb, although Sewell said Speaker was a good manager.
[SPEAKER_03]: Speaker was a great manager.
[SPEAKER_03]: See, Speaker was with me while at Washington.
[SPEAKER_03]: Speaker and Cobb came over to Washington.
[SPEAKER_03]: In 27, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Two years after they quit.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I guess they like, they expect the players to play as good as they played.
[SPEAKER_02]: That must be it.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about, well, Walter Johnson, was he able to communicate his ideas to the players, or was it he just couldn't?
[SPEAKER_03]: Just couldn't put it over.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know why.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, I wouldn't say that he didn't, but he'd say, he'd just tell them, say, just throw that ball by them.
[SPEAKER_03]: The harder the pitcher'd throw it, the harder they'd hit it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, Walter Johnson, I didn't see him in his heyday.
[SPEAKER_03]: They said he really had something.
[SPEAKER_03]: A little old fellow, Muddy Ruehl, about so high, weighed about 120 pounds soaking wet.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a catcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he was one of the greatest ballplayers of all time.
[SPEAKER_03]: You remember Muddy Ruehl.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a great catcher and a fine fellow.
[SPEAKER_02]: Always smoking a pipe.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right, and a fine fellow, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was he a lawyer?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_03]: Moe Berg was, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: Bo was in Chicago with you?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, he was there before I was there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, when you sat down in Minneapolis, did that disturb you at all?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: I knew I was coming back.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had it down here that I was coming back.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was just temporary.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was Joe Kelly or Mike Kelly up there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Mike Kelly was the owner and the manager.
[SPEAKER_03]: He used to sit on the bench and holler at us.
[SPEAKER_03]: We'd be in a ballgame.
[SPEAKER_03]: A man would be getting us out.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd say, my gosh, y'all going to let that Yankee Doodle pitcher get you out?
[SPEAKER_03]: Get up there and hit that ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, we had a good year in Minneapolis.
[SPEAKER_02]: We had a good stretch there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'll switch this off for a moment.
[SPEAKER_02]: And back with Washington in 29.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was 276 there, a pretty good year.
[SPEAKER_02]: 29, yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: So you must have played regular that year.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was, I guess, in between Harris and Johnson.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, Harris' second baseman and Buddy Myers.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right in between those two.
[SPEAKER_02]: Buddy came up about then.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, Buddy was over with Boston Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was traded to Washington, traded for him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, then that's when you went.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's when I went to White Sox in 31.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, you didn't play too much in 30 here.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I told you I was a utility man.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had me all over the place.
[SPEAKER_03]: Back then,
[SPEAKER_03]: We only had one utility man.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now they have three or four.
[SPEAKER_03]: And the relief pitchers, they only had two, a right-hander and a left.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Fred Marbury and Garland Braxton.
[SPEAKER_03]: You remember Garland Braxton?
[SPEAKER_03]: I remember that name.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a left-hander.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Big Fred Marbury, who later turned umpire, was the right-hander.
[SPEAKER_02]: Roger Peckinpah, I come from Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: I talked to him a couple of times in Cleveland the last few years.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he was saying about Marbury.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said it was Marbury who first convinced him of the value of relief pitching.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Up until then, he wasn't sure they served a role, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: But the way Marbury could come in and go for a short stretch, he was convinced.
[SPEAKER_03]: I saw Marbury lose two games in one day, and one man won both of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: 1930, we were fighting Philadelphia Athletics.
[SPEAKER_03]: First place, they had a ball club then.
[SPEAKER_03]: Simmons played the first game.
[SPEAKER_03]: He hit a home run in the ninth inning to win the ball game.
[SPEAKER_03]: Mr. Mack rested him the second game because he had a bad leg.
[SPEAKER_03]: Came up in the ninth, and they brought Marbury in to pitch.
[SPEAKER_03]: Pinch, pitch.
[SPEAKER_03]: Total, then he hit another home run.
[SPEAKER_03]: He won both ball games, and Marbury lost both ball games in one day.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's quite a day he liked to forget.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you more comfortable at any one of these positions than the other?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I'll tell you that it was a strange,
[SPEAKER_03]: To me, I went up as a shortstop.
[SPEAKER_03]: I played shortstop in college.
[SPEAKER_03]: And like I said, my first game was at third base.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I was lost.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then they wanted me to train for second base.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think second base was, I learned to keep from getting the double play broken up.
[SPEAKER_03]: I always kept my feet apart.
[SPEAKER_03]: If they hit me, they'd knock off one leg.
[SPEAKER_03]: I could throw off the other one.
[SPEAKER_03]: If they hit this leg, I could throw off the left one.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about your arm?
[SPEAKER_02]: Was it suited for any of those positions?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_02]: Shortstop, you need the better arm.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: I could throw in either position.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you get spiked much down at second base or at any of the bases?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I got shins all over my leg.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: You know what that is, don't you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Cartilage.
[SPEAKER_03]: Both sides of my knee, my right knee.
[SPEAKER_02]: When did that happen?
[SPEAKER_03]: That's when people slide in to you and knock you up.
[SPEAKER_03]: You don't know when it happens, but it develops later.
[SPEAKER_02]: I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I had this arm operated on, a lot of bone out of there, chips out of the elbow.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, some of those fellas up there slide into you and hold you.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never shall forget one day we were playing Washington.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was with the White Sox.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, now you watch this fella.
[SPEAKER_03]: I told the umpire, I said, Jake Powell gets on base.
[SPEAKER_03]: There's a ground ball when he comes to second.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'll dive first and he'll grab me around the legs to break up the double play.
[SPEAKER_03]: Funnest thing, it happened.
[SPEAKER_03]: He came down and caught me, and I never did throw the ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: The umpire called both of them out.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, they came out on the field, you holler.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he told them why.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because he had me around the legs where I couldn't throw.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's a good old Jake Powell, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: You remember Jake?
[SPEAKER_02]: Jake's a Maryland boy.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a sciatic nerve problem, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, he did.
[SPEAKER_02]: I saw him get a seizure at the Cleveland once.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, bad.
[SPEAKER_02]: Kicking and screaming.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bad.
[SPEAKER_03]: Jake was a policeman, I think, in the winter.
[SPEAKER_02]: up there in the middle.
[SPEAKER_03]: You got a little trouble saying what he did to them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I think the greatest ball club that I saw the time I was playing up there was the Yankers of 27.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now they had a ball club.
[SPEAKER_03]: The next greatest was 30th Philadelphia Athletics in 1930 with Grove, Wahlberg,
[SPEAKER_03]: Rommel, Earnshaw, Simmons.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Before he died, I talked him up in Norwalk, Ohio.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had Mickey Corcoran, had Fox, had Bishop at second, Bolle at short, you know, and Dykes at third.
[SPEAKER_02]: I saw that play.
[SPEAKER_02]: My first baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you see Simmons?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I saw those guys.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you see Mule Haas?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was a great play.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you see Bing Miller?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was the best right-handed hitter for curveballs around the league.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was the best right-handed hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: He hit that ball to right field.
[SPEAKER_03]: I can never forget Jimmy Fox swinging the bat.
[SPEAKER_03]: He scared you when he missed.
[SPEAKER_03]: Cut his sleeves off way up there.
[SPEAKER_03]: You see that big muscle up there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Looked like he was squeezing sodas down in the back when he was...
[SPEAKER_03]: It is a tremendous strength in those arms.
[SPEAKER_02]: My first game was in 29, so I never saw the great Yankee teams just before.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I did see the great athletic teams.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: 30.
[SPEAKER_02]: 30 and 31.
[SPEAKER_02]: I saw the murder clue.
[SPEAKER_03]: I grew up in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_03]: You could go to bed at night
[SPEAKER_03]: Say, well, Grove's gonna pitch tomorrow, and you know he's gonna pitch.
[SPEAKER_03]: They'd advertise Grove pitching.
[SPEAKER_03]: Know you ain't gonna get a thing but a fastball?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, he didn't have to look for a curve, cause he didn't have a curve.
[SPEAKER_03]: You still couldn't hit it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Pop it up in the air somewhere.
[SPEAKER_03]: I guess Johnson threw off fastballs, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_03]: They said he did.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never did see Johnson pitching this prime.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had arms all the way down his, hands all the way down to his knees when he walked along.
[SPEAKER_03]: He kind of slang the ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: Grove was the fastest man.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, Feller,
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever bat against him?
[SPEAKER_02]: You're still playing?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was the man I could hit.
[SPEAKER_03]: I could really hit him.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he had the best curveball.
[SPEAKER_03]: Go along with it.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's a good fastball.
[SPEAKER_03]: I won two or three games against Bob.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's just one of those things.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, Mel Harder, he was the toughest guy for me.
[SPEAKER_03]: You remember little Mel McCleveland?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, he was tough.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was our hero.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, he was a great little pitcher and a fine fellow.
[SPEAKER_03]: He won over 200 bowl games.
[SPEAKER_03]: So was Bob.
[SPEAKER_02]: Bob's a good fellow, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: His last name is just right.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's a good fella.
[SPEAKER_02]: I heard him talk just a month or so ago down in Marietta.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, you did?
[SPEAKER_02]: Where I teach.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had a College World Series there this year.
[SPEAKER_01]: He came down to speak.
[SPEAKER_01]: Told a couple of interesting stories.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, how'd you feel about, who was the trade of the White Sox with again?
[SPEAKER_02]: You went with Bump Hadley?
[SPEAKER_03]: Went with Bump Hadley and Sam Jones.
[SPEAKER_02]: And who were they?
[SPEAKER_03]: Who went over there was Carl Reynolds and Johnny Kerr.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, Kerr.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did you feel about that trade?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did it make you...
[SPEAKER_03]: I wanted to play ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't care if I went to Flacto, just so I played ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: It didn't hurt me to be traded over there.
[SPEAKER_03]: However, they had a trade up before it came out in the papers that they were going to do it, but it didn't happen.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was Jones and Hadley and myself going to the Yankees, but I didn't get there.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was that World Series money.
[SPEAKER_03]: Something happened, they called it off.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, that was a World Series money.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm looking forward to going to the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_03]: Tell me a little bit about Sam Jones.
[SPEAKER_03]: Sam Jones was a great father, and he was a good pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's just a good man.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, a real good man.
[SPEAKER_02]: He won 200 and some games.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think so.
[SPEAKER_03]: The deacon, we called him.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was his nickname, the deacon.
[SPEAKER_03]: Sam and Ted Lonson said, we always budded together.
[SPEAKER_03]: Tell me a little bit about Ted Lonson, too, and some of your experiences with him.
[SPEAKER_03]: What kind of a chap?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, great.
[SPEAKER_03]: One of the finest that ever lived on and off the field.
[SPEAKER_03]: Not just on the field, off the field, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: And one of the toughest pitchers.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, he didn't let up.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd go from the start till he got out of there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, he'd bear down and throw that ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a great pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, if Ted had been with a club like the Yankees, he'd have been a third game winner.
[SPEAKER_03]: We could get him some runs, but we couldn't get him enough.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he was a great pitcher and a great man with it.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's down at Vinton, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: Vinton, Louisiana.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, he's had eye trouble.
[SPEAKER_02]: I haven't seen him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd like to interview him sometime.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, he had the cataracts removed and he had detached retinas.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's had eye trouble.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's down in Venton, Louisiana, just out of New Orleans.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, we're going to make a trip next summer down through the South and Southwest.
[SPEAKER_02]: Maybe I can stop by and see him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he's a wonderful fellow, I hope.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd love to stop by.
[SPEAKER_02]: He came right off the college campus, too, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_02]: Baylor.
[SPEAKER_02]: Baylor, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Didn't he pitch a no-hitter pretty quick after his?
[SPEAKER_03]: I just don't remember, but I think you're right.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think you're right.
[SPEAKER_03]: It wasn't too long.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was in the big time.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think you're right.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a no-hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, Detroit had a great ball club that one year, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: At York, and Greenberg, Rogale, Charlie Gerringer, one of the best second basemen that ever lived, I think.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was my man, a man that I would look forward to.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Ed Cochran, Catching, they had a good ball club over there.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they had a fellow there so big he could wire that left field out when Grove was pitching, they said.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bob Fothergate.
[SPEAKER_02]: You remember him?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, he'd hit the way 300 pounds.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd hit line drives up in the left field.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did he take very good care of himself off the field?
[SPEAKER_03]: I just don't know a thing about him.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's from Massillon, Ohio.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: I get a lot of cards and a lot of autographs now from people all over the country.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've got four or five of you now.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've got to sign up and send to them.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd like to hear from them.
[SPEAKER_02]: How'd you like playing in Comiskey Park with those long fences?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I was never a home-run hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was mostly a hit-and-run man, and it didn't matter much about the long ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now Simmons, when he came there, after he left athletics, he'd hit one back and they'd catch it right up against him.
[SPEAKER_02]: He'd say, uh-oh, that'd been a home run in Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_03]: And it would have to.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know, the wind, nine games out of ten, the wind's blowing in there.
[SPEAKER_03]: And we always, between innings, we'd turn around.
[SPEAKER_03]: There's a flag in center field.
[SPEAKER_03]: We'd watch that flag and tell where the wind was blowing, where to go catch the ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_03]: Zeke went over up there in your time?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: Zeke used to take two steps off of first base and say, hey, Jackie boy, there's that line.
[SPEAKER_03]: Don't you come over that line.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'll catch that ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: If you come over that line, I'll get everything inside that line.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's about two steps.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Zeke was a fine feller.
[SPEAKER_03]: But you could totally see Cabal at first base.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd reach out to get it, and if his foot wasn't on the bag, the ball just went on by.
[SPEAKER_03]: He wouldn't get off the bag and catch the ball and then tag the man, like Joe Koo.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, we had a great infield.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Marvin Owen came over there, Luke Appling.
[SPEAKER_03]: I played second base, and Joe Koo.
[SPEAKER_03]: You remember Joe Koo used to be a watcher?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a first baseman.
[SPEAKER_03]: We had a good ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: Great infield.
[SPEAKER_02]: defensively and feel one of the best in the country, I thought.
[SPEAKER_02]: Zeke wasn't too mobile then, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: He just didn't... Zeke could hit that ball now.
[SPEAKER_02]: He couldn't run, but he...
[SPEAKER_02]: He could hit that ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't have to run.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he just let the ball go by one field and that was all.
[SPEAKER_03]: Zeke was a wonder.
[SPEAKER_02]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_02]: Henry Vanura.
[SPEAKER_03]: Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_02]: Quite a comedian, was he?
[SPEAKER_03]: He walked in the hotel in, let's see, in Boston in the 90s there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I want some watermelon.
[SPEAKER_03]: He got him watermelon, walked in the lobby and the girls and the boys all dressed in the evening clothes.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had a big ball there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Zeke had a watermelon on his shoulder and had a red cap behind him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm gonna get me some of that good New Orleans watermelon.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a wonder.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had a bad leg.
[SPEAKER_03]: Back then, where the broadcast from upstairs above Comiskey Park, they had to climb a ladder to get up there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Zeke went up there and he kept talking, talking, and Dykes said, Zeke, you better get back in that ballgame.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, Papa, as soon as my groin gets well, I'll be ready to play.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, well, you better hurry up.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, let me tell you something.
[SPEAKER_03]: Asked him two or three days later.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, now, Zeke, let me tell you something.
[SPEAKER_03]: If you don't hurry up and get back in that ballgame, that train you've been talking about going down to good old New Orleans, if you don't hurry up and get back in that ballgame, you're going to be on that train going to New Orleans.
[SPEAKER_03]: Dykes was a great man.
[SPEAKER_03]: He knew who to pat on the back.
[SPEAKER_03]: He knew who to kick around.
[SPEAKER_03]: He just knew how to manage a ball club.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_02]: How'd he handle you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he need any help?
[SPEAKER_02]: Didn't bother me.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, the man next to me, Luke Appling over there, aches and pains.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd start to holler, oh, my leg's hurting, my shin's hurting.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd get about five hits.
[SPEAKER_03]: We were playing in Washington one day.
[SPEAKER_03]: Somebody took his bat up in batting practice and broke it.
[SPEAKER_03]: He hollered at the bench when he went up to hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who broke my bat?
[SPEAKER_03]: Who broke my bat?
[SPEAKER_03]: Him, Luke.
[SPEAKER_03]: Took a new one, went up there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Sangled to right field.
[SPEAKER_03]: Next time he went to bat, all of us on the bench.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who broke Luke's bat?
Pow!
[SPEAKER_03]: Sangled to right field.
[SPEAKER_03]: Five for five.
[SPEAKER_03]: That year he hit .388 and led the league.
[SPEAKER_03]: Dykes had all of us yell, who broke Luke's bat?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he really foul off all those pitches he didn't want to hit?
[SPEAKER_03]: Purpose?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't think so.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he had such a good eye.
[SPEAKER_03]: There's a reason those balls are foul.
[SPEAKER_03]: We'd get a big crowd out there, he'd start singing, I'd say, what in the world's the matter with you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Before, when the ballgame started.
[SPEAKER_03]: You are my sunshine, my pretty sunshine.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he'd cut down the, I'd say, what in the world's the matter with you?
[SPEAKER_03]: 40,000 people up here.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, I'm just unlaxing a little.
[SPEAKER_03]: You are my sunshine, my pretty sunshine.
[SPEAKER_03]: After the first inning was over, he was all right.
[SPEAKER_03]: He sang, he cut down the old pine tree.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, you are my sunshine.
[SPEAKER_03]: But, I said, now Luke, that's all right.
[SPEAKER_03]: But one day he started singing.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sweet little Arnie, if you remember that song.
[SPEAKER_03]: If you heard him singing, when he got to that sweet little Arnie, I said, that has to stop.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a card.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a great ball player, though.
[SPEAKER_03]: How about fielding?
[SPEAKER_03]: Is he pretty good out there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Who, Luke?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, when he first came up, both of us kicked it all over the infield.
[SPEAKER_02]: But after we got working together, it's fine.
[SPEAKER_02]: How would you work your double plays, say you got a right-hand hitter coming up?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, it all depends on how you pitch to him.
[SPEAKER_03]: If you're going to pitch him inside, naturally you shortstop cover.
[SPEAKER_03]: But if you're going to pitch him outside of curveball, he might hit the right field.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd give a signal on each pitch as to who was to cover.
[SPEAKER_03]: You'd wait and see what the pitcher did?
[SPEAKER_03]: As soon as they called for the pitch, I'd give him the signal.
[SPEAKER_03]: Open mouth, he was to cover.
[SPEAKER_03]: Closed mouth, I was to cover.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: I often wondered what was being said.
[SPEAKER_03]: We didn't say anything.
[SPEAKER_03]: We just had to sign.
[SPEAKER_03]: See, we'd come up, open mouth, you to cover, close mouth, I'm to cover.
[SPEAKER_03]: And you'd go in and sometimes you'd tell the pitcher, too, if it was a man that hit always to left field, I'd holler to the pitcher, say, hey, Ted, give that ball to me, not second base.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was it easy to work with Luke around second base?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: Great.
[SPEAKER_03]: Great to work with him.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a good man to work with.
[SPEAKER_02]: We led the league, I think, for second and double plays, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever take part in a triple play?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: Never.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't get close.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you ever hear of anybody named Smead Jolly?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I got a funny one I want to tell you on Smead.
[SPEAKER_03]: They all told it, so I guess I should.
[SPEAKER_03]: In Boston, out in the left field, there used to be a dump, a hill up there, a mound up there, and then the fences up on that mound.
[SPEAKER_03]: One day, Smead missed a couple of balls out there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Donnie Bush, they say it now.
[SPEAKER_03]: This is a story.
[SPEAKER_03]: Took him out before the ball game and hit him balls up there, and he'd just catch them and catch them and catch them.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then when the game started, someone hit a ball out there, and Smead just fell all down that bank field box.
[SPEAKER_03]: Came in, Donnie got up and said, Jolly, I practiced you.
[SPEAKER_03]: Why in the world do you catch that ball?
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, well, you taught me how to go up the bank.
[SPEAKER_03]: You didn't tell me how to come down.
[SPEAKER_03]: They said he fell right on his face.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, that's the one they told him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about the three errors in one play?
[SPEAKER_02]: Remember that one?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I wasn't with them then.
[SPEAKER_02]: Joey Sewell told that one yesterday.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was up in Cleveland, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: We was coming back in Cleveland in the cab one day.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's when our ball club was just trading everybody on us.
[SPEAKER_03]: Everybody was trading.
[SPEAKER_03]: When you'd see the morning, come to breakfast the next morning, shake hands with a different ball player.
[SPEAKER_03]: Smead's coming back in the cab saying, ha, they won't trade old Pardner.
[SPEAKER_03]: Old Pardner's got his place made here.
[SPEAKER_03]: Got into the hotel.
[SPEAKER_03]: Joe Barry, who said, hey, it's me.
[SPEAKER_03]: Come here a minute.
[SPEAKER_03]: Said, you've been traded to the St. Louis Browns.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Bump Hadley and I in the same town, Cleveland, they were just trading ball players over.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bump and I, the way we would do when we'd come into a hotel, one fellow would have the red cap, take the bags up the room, while the other one, I got him a milkshake or something like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then the other one would come in.
[SPEAKER_03]: But Bump went out that night.
[SPEAKER_03]: to get his milk shake, and I took his bag up to him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I didn't get in the room good until Mr. Joe Barrett called and said, Jack, said, is Bump there?
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, no, he's going out to get a drink.
[SPEAKER_03]: Tonight was my night to bring these bags up.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, well, when he comes back, tell him not to unpack, that he's just been sold to St. Louis Browns.
[SPEAKER_03]: So he came in.
[SPEAKER_03]: I told him we had a good cry.
[SPEAKER_03]: Had a good cry, and he left and caught the midnight train from St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_03]: They just traded you around like that, huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, we used to call Lou Fonseca.
[SPEAKER_03]: The man with three ballclubs had one coming, one playing, and one going.
[SPEAKER_03]: And for two years there, one year anyway, he had them going everywhere.
[SPEAKER_03]: On the way, going, and coming, and there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was responsible for this?
[SPEAKER_02]: Lew himself, or Comiskey?
[SPEAKER_03]: I just don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's what we wondered too, who was doing all that trading.
[SPEAKER_03]: Harry Grabener.
[SPEAKER_03]: Might have been.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know who it was.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I know one thing.
[SPEAKER_03]: I bet you we had more new ballplayers on that ballclub that year.
[SPEAKER_03]: Any ball clubs ever had?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did Jolly call himself old partner?
[SPEAKER_03]: Old partner.
[SPEAKER_03]: Watch old partner go now.
[SPEAKER_03]: Old Smee Jolly.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is he pretty bright or not so bright?
[SPEAKER_02]: I won't judge that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know about that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Baseball wise?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know about it.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's a good fella.
[SPEAKER_03]: And you know what, nine out of ten ballplayers, you hear people complaining about them, this and that, but nine out of ten ballplayers love to play baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: A man that's a success in baseball has got to love it.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the first rule in the book with me, is you've got to love it.
[SPEAKER_03]: If you don't, well I'll just take a little case, a little example of that.
[SPEAKER_03]: I went to Lakeland, Florida, spring training, a long time ago.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ted Lyons was down there, asked me to come down to his spring training.
[SPEAKER_03]: Of course, I was blind and I lost my sight at 40.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had a boy,
[SPEAKER_03]: Down there was a young outfielder.
[SPEAKER_03]: Had everything in the world.
[SPEAKER_03]: Everything.
[SPEAKER_03]: Build, arm, hit, do everything.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you know he never did make it?
[SPEAKER_03]: He finally quit because he didn't like it.
[SPEAKER_03]: They said, you see that boy out there?
[SPEAKER_03]: He doesn't like to play ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the reason.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he lost out.
[SPEAKER_03]: He sure did.
[SPEAKER_03]: You've got to love it to play it.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's just like business.
[SPEAKER_03]: You've got to love it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've always told people semi-pro ball is where you have your fun.
[SPEAKER_03]: Major League Baseball is all business.
[SPEAKER_03]: You better play while you're out there, not fool around.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, but you still enjoy it, though.
[SPEAKER_03]: You love it.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's what I say.
[SPEAKER_03]: If you love it, you do.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't mean like it.
[SPEAKER_03]: You've got to love it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_02]: It must have been a big thrill up there, playing in the big time with all these stars.
[SPEAKER_03]: Get Wadsworth, Gehrig, and all of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Big thrill.
[SPEAKER_03]: But the biggest thrill of all was when Johnny Dobbs told me I was sold to Washington.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was my first big thrill.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I had a big thrill going through the,
[SPEAKER_03]: Alabama Sports Hall of Fame up here, two years ago.
[SPEAKER_03]: Last year, this past year, it was 76, I think, when I was elected to the...
[SPEAKER_03]: They have 36 people to elect men to it, I think, over the state.
[SPEAKER_03]: Joe Sewell and Rick Stevenson were elected, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: I lost my sight in 1940 and had to quit.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you were playing with the White Sox in 32-1.
[SPEAKER_02]: Till 40, till I lost my sight.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, you played with them all those years.
[SPEAKER_02]: Till I lost my sight.
[SPEAKER_02]: How many managers did you have over there now?
[SPEAKER_02]: Two.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just Fonseca and Dykes.
[SPEAKER_02]: Fonseca and Dykes.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you want to hear about my sight?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't mind talking about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I would like to hear about that, yeah, if you don't mind.
[SPEAKER_03]: We played, we were fixing to break camp.
[SPEAKER_03]: We were playing Hollywood, California.
[SPEAKER_03]: We was playing Connie Mack's analytics exhibition game.
[SPEAKER_03]: Went to bat three times, had three hits.
[SPEAKER_03]: Went into the clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_03]: Took my shower and felt like I had some soap in my eye.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I just washed it out like I always do.
[SPEAKER_03]: Thought it was all right.
[SPEAKER_03]: Next day, we went on with the Yuma Arizona and went from Yuma to Tucson.
[SPEAKER_03]: And before that, it was Tucson.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I told Dax, I said, now Jim, I said, I can put my hand up on my left eye and I look out my right and I have the numbers on the player's back run together.
[SPEAKER_03]: It doesn't look right.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, well, since you're having trouble, he said, you get your leg exercise, run around the park, and you won't have to play today.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I ran around the park, and then we went into Phoenix.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was on Sunday morning, and I woke up.
[SPEAKER_03]: I looked up at the light, and I saw the ring around the light.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, there's something still wrong.
[SPEAKER_03]: He asked the manager of the hotel where he could find an eye specialist, so he could call an eye specialist.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I went over to his office, and he examined them.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, I want to go talk to your trainer.
[SPEAKER_03]: and your manager, have them there at the place when I get over at your hotel.
[SPEAKER_03]: He came over and that was on Sunday morning.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said the best thing for him to do is go back to Chicago.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I wired my wife, and actually that tore her all to pieces, but I'd been hitting nine, all of this, and came back.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then to August, then until, that was in April, I think.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then August, sight was completely gone of the right eye, and I played about nine games that year.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was the first one to wear a helmet.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was a homemade helmet.
[SPEAKER_03]: I still got it here somewhere.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's just a little old piece of metal across here, two air flaps over it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Sounded like a seashell roar.
[SPEAKER_03]: You get up near the ball, it's like you're hitting a pumpkin.
[SPEAKER_03]: I played about nine games.
[SPEAKER_03]: Got a hit the first time I went to bat.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know what the trainer said?
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, you ought to have been blind a long time ago.
[SPEAKER_03]: And at the end of that year, I went on to the baseball meeting.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I guess I made a mistake, but I asked for my release.
[SPEAKER_03]: I should have stuck around and got some of that pension money, but I didn't.
[SPEAKER_03]: See, the pension came in in 47, and I had to quit in 40.
[SPEAKER_03]: I could have stayed there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had in mind, what I had in mind was playing two or three more years, and I was going to try to be a coach.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never did want to be a manager, but I sure wanted to be a coach.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I may think I want to get that pension, but I missed it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Missed it by seven years.
[SPEAKER_03]: How about the left eye?
[SPEAKER_03]: It went out in 43.
[SPEAKER_03]: I came back home, and I was elected county tax collector with the help of my wife.
[SPEAKER_03]: We ran the office here for 12 years.
[SPEAKER_03]: We were elected two terms.
[SPEAKER_03]: In 43, I got my first seeing eye dog.
[SPEAKER_03]: This is my sixth one.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, fifth one.
[SPEAKER_03]: This is my fifth dog.
[SPEAKER_03]: And all of them had been boxers.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I would get, you see that cassettes?
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd get Braille records from Talladega over here.
[SPEAKER_03]: I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the seeing eye, I mean that's the blind place.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had a strange thing that happened last time was the seeing eye.
[SPEAKER_02]: What's that?
[SPEAKER_03]: I had six students there that was born blind.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I played around, they called me Papa Jack after they found out how old I was.
[SPEAKER_03]: And the manager of the Seeing Eye, the owner, the president, said, Jack, I sure do want to thank you.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, you gave all these kids a lot of inspiration up here, because in the summer they have young kids, see.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, I gave them nothing.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, they gave me inspiration.
[SPEAKER_03]: You remember when the kids were all born blind about the oxygen business?
[SPEAKER_03]: You remember back there was a spell there, something about didn't get enough oxygen or didn't?
[SPEAKER_00]: And it tells in there about the year, the Jack's Greatest Year.
[SPEAKER_03]: Show Mr. Murdoch my helmet.
[SPEAKER_03]: Have you got it somewhere down here?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I've got it.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the first helmet that was more.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was just saving that for the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_02]: Are there any pictures, extra pictures of him at all in his playing days that he might sign for me?
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll tell you, I was just about to give it to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm so afraid I'll give him my hat.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't have any left, but I'm real proud.
[SPEAKER_03]: Give one of my little bags.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, you may have that right up.
[SPEAKER_00]: I appreciate that very much.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just as it went on to say now, what he told you about winning the first night game in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: My fella was pitching.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jack really got the only hit that night.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, we had three hits.
[SPEAKER_03]: I got two of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: We got three hits.
[SPEAKER_00]: But anyway, and another thing, the year that he got
[SPEAKER_00]: made the most money, which was nothing to sell us starting what it is today.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had $229.
[SPEAKER_00]: He batted in more run than the man led to lead.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it tells about, I think he was second or third in the old
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I'm 79.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wasn't, uh... You, you were seven and a third.
[SPEAKER_00]: But anyway, I thought you might be interested in that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was pleased I came fine so long.
[SPEAKER_03]: When did you get married?
[SPEAKER_03]: See if you can find some 36.
[SPEAKER_03]: See if you can't find some of those little snapshots.
[SPEAKER_02]: This was just a little... Did you like baseball?
[SPEAKER_03]: She was crazy about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yes, I was crazy about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we, I wasn't in it long enough, really, for you to see.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had one year where it had lived, and the rest of it was nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Trouble.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bad knee.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bad leg.
[SPEAKER_00]: Operation on my knee.
[SPEAKER_03]: She stuck with me though.
[SPEAKER_02]: What happened, was your knee again just the, did one thing happen there, or is it accumulation of the cartilage?
[SPEAKER_02]: Cartilage, and cartilage on both sides of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was in 36?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, that's a long time before then.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know just now when it was.
[SPEAKER_03]: Sam Jones, get that quote Sam Jones made.
[SPEAKER_03]: He knows Sam.
[SPEAKER_03]: Didn't know him.
[SPEAKER_03]: You hear people talk about C&I dogs, they're wonderful.
[SPEAKER_03]: They take care of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: This is my fifth boxer.
[SPEAKER_03]: The reason people always ask me why do they have German Shepherds and C&I, why do so many people use them?
[SPEAKER_03]: That breeding division is Shepherds.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's why.
[SPEAKER_00]: We've got stacks and stacks of scrapbooks, but I just can't take them out.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who kept the scrapbooks?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you keep them?
[SPEAKER_03]: She kept most of them, but somebody sent me two and I don't know yet who did it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Show him one of them, just let him look at it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't mean to look through it, just show him how it's shaped.
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay, leave it alone, just leave it alone.
[SPEAKER_00]: Somebody left them at the hotel for me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I came in from the ballpark one day and they weren't there.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's so interesting how the wives often keep the scrapbooks for the husbands.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, she's got all kinds.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about umpire relations?
[SPEAKER_02]: Good, good all of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: One put me out, I've never been put out, but two ball games.
[SPEAKER_03]: One I threw the ball out against the ground, I know the man's out at first.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Mr. Connelly was supervisor of umpires, and he told me later that he called that umpire down for that, said he was out there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Said that umpire missed that play and said he shouldn't have put you out of the game for throwing that ball against the ground.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the first time I was ever put out of a game.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was the umpire?
[SPEAKER_03]: Red Ornsby.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then we went over to Boston one day, and I had a broken thumb.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had it in a cast, and I was sitting up on the top step of the dugout.
[SPEAKER_03]: Somebody at the bench was yelling to Luke Cole, yelling, yelling.
[SPEAKER_03]: He looked over, and he said, you get out of here!
[SPEAKER_02]: Luke Cole.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, McGowan, what did you think of Bill McGowan?
[SPEAKER_03]: Bill McGowan was a good umpire.
[SPEAKER_03]: Harry Geisel, you remember Harry Geisel?
[SPEAKER_03]: One of the best.
[SPEAKER_03]: One of the men, you know what he'd do?
[SPEAKER_03]: If you run up to Harry and start talking, say, now Harry, I know that man was out.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now so and so and so and so.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, now listen, Jack.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the way I called it.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the way I saw it.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I'm not going to change it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, now, what are you going to do?
[SPEAKER_03]: The ones that jaw back at you, that's where the arguments start.
[SPEAKER_03]: When you jaw back at them, what?
[SPEAKER_03]: Bill Guthrie used to take them.
[SPEAKER_03]: You remember Bill Guthrie?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I was going to ask you about Guthrie.
[SPEAKER_03]: I bagged a man out a second, I thought he was out, and I looked up.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, that man was out!
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, no, it was the same.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, well, it was close then!
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, listen, kiddo, there ain't no close ones.
[SPEAKER_03]: They either this or they that.
[SPEAKER_03]: You remember how he talked?
[SPEAKER_03]: An Italian dog said, either this or they that.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I kept my mouth shut from that old Bill I mean about, because I knew he was going to say, either this or that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bill Summers was a great umpire.
[SPEAKER_03]: You remember Bill Summers?
[SPEAKER_02]: Big heavy settler, a little heavy settler.
[SPEAKER_03]: Right, big chet.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'll tell you another man used to be a good... George Moriarty was a good umpire.
[SPEAKER_03]: Billy Evans.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was Deneen still umpiring your time?
[SPEAKER_03]: Deneen.
[SPEAKER_03]: And what's that other one used to go around with him all the time?
[SPEAKER_03]: Hildebrand?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was Deneen, Hildebrand, and three of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Hildebrand, Deneen, and I just can't remember the other names of them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Roy Van Graafelen.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I remember Roy real well.
[SPEAKER_03]: Dick Allen.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the one, Dineen and Nalin.
[SPEAKER_03]: They always worked together, looked like.
[SPEAKER_03]: Dineen and Nalin.
[SPEAKER_03]: They were good umpires.
[SPEAKER_03]: They were good fellas.
[SPEAKER_03]: I got along with them fine on the ball field.
[SPEAKER_03]: Of course, off the ball field, back then you never did see them.
[SPEAKER_03]: They passed a rule one time, you know, they thought there was something going on and they wouldn't let you go up and talk to people in the stand.
[SPEAKER_03]: A fella came up there one day and called me on me going, I wouldn't go.
[SPEAKER_03]: fellow from my hometown, and I went in there at the ballgame, and I saw him.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, I want to ask you something.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, what is it?
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, why wouldn't you come up and speak to me?
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, well, the president just made a real $500 fine for us to go up and shake hands.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, I understand.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't see you until after the game.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he did.
[SPEAKER_03]: There was some gambling going on some way, and he thought there was something wrong.
[SPEAKER_03]: You remember when Judge Landis was commissioner?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, what he said.
[SPEAKER_03]: It went that way.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you ever meet the judge?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: Years ago.
[SPEAKER_03]: He used to come out to White Sox Park all the time.
[SPEAKER_03]: Remember that hat he used to wear?
[SPEAKER_03]: Used to wear that hat like a snozzled orange all the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he talk to the players at all?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, at the ballpark.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just speak to you, that was all.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just speak to you.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's all.
[SPEAKER_03]: There was some great umpires.
[SPEAKER_03]: There was some great players in baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: Lord have mercy, way back from 27 through 40, I saw some good ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_03]: And there wasn't only great ballplayers, there were great men off the ball field.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, a lot of people used to think ballplayers are roughnecks.
[SPEAKER_03]: And some fellas told me that before I went up there, before the college players started to come in, they were kind of roughnecks.
[SPEAKER_03]: But you know, after the college players got to go, they'd go to Springtree and go to these hotels and go to these ball clubs and get them to come stop at their hotel.
[SPEAKER_03]: But before that, somebody didn't want me there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Remember Tony Pyatt?
[SPEAKER_03]: Tony Pyatt, one of my best friends.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: He's the one that helped get that knife for me in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_03]: See, I had a knife in Chicago in 58, I think.
[SPEAKER_03]: 48, 48.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had a knife there, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Big knife.
[SPEAKER_02]: But you were living here then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've lived here every winter since I started playing baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: I talked to Tony Pyatt.
[SPEAKER_02]: He runs the big automobile dealership.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's got a heart condition.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I have too.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm wearing my third pacemaker now.
[SPEAKER_03]: I got my third pacemaker just put in about a month ago, two months ago, third one.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they're doing wonders.
[SPEAKER_02]: He put on a night for Monty Stratton, or I guess he got that car from Monty Stratton when he had a night.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, they gave money, I think, enough to buy a farm out there, too, in Greenville, Texas.
[SPEAKER_03]: He lives in Greenville, Texas.
[SPEAKER_03]: You ever go see Monty?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I've never seen him.
[SPEAKER_03]: You ought to go see him.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's a good boy.
[SPEAKER_03]: There's never been a better fellow anywhere than Monty Stratton.
[SPEAKER_03]: had that terrible accident.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he was right in his prime.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had won, I think, 15 games a year before.
[SPEAKER_03]: And we were really counting on it.
[SPEAKER_03]: That had to happen.
[SPEAKER_03]: And the strangest thing, we were going to Chicago for an operation on my arm or something, and we stopped it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Been since Indiana, spent the night there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Next morning, I went down, went up the newsstand.
[SPEAKER_03]: I told them I'm on the Chicago Tribune.
[SPEAKER_03]: There's headlines that Monty Stratton had shot his leg.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ah!
[SPEAKER_03]: It was a bad, bad, bad trip.
[SPEAKER_03]: We'd get out there on that field and put on that wooden leg, a piece of batting practice, stick it out and catch the ground ball, and it was goody, goody, didn't hit, didn't hurt me.
[SPEAKER_03]: It hit, boop, it hit the bounce hole.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he'd come in the shower, leg was cut off about right there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Soap it up good, come hopping in there on that one leg, get you right up there, throw that soap bar.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was the one that took it.
[SPEAKER_03]: He took it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I saw Joe Sewell play ball down here at this ballpark.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was named after me years and years ago.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was playing with a town team called Eclectic.
[SPEAKER_03]: The final score of the game was 1-0.
[SPEAKER_03]: Eclectic beat Clanton.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that man hit the home run.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was a cross-hand hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: First one I'd ever seen.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I still remember his name was Woodall.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that was in 1918 or something like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I still remember that ballgame.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I asked Joe not long ago if he remembered it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Sure boy, I do.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was in that ballgame.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he said, that's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the man that hit it.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's a lawyer over here at Tallis.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, yes, I do.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was in that game.
[SPEAKER_03]: They were dressed, back then we didn't have any pastries.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they walked through town in red uniforms, bright red.
[SPEAKER_03]: And when they got hot,
[SPEAKER_03]: And those new uniforms started melting.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had red run all over them.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was looking about it, and you'd never see.
[SPEAKER_02]: Didn't the White Sox have a black uniform?
[SPEAKER_02]: One time, when I first joined them.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was really revolutionary then, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Because it was hot as a devil.
[SPEAKER_02]: I wonder why they did that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was hot as fire.
[SPEAKER_02]: I remember seeing you guys play at Lake Park with that navy blue or whatever it was.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the road uniform.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Johnny Watwood playing first base.
[SPEAKER_03]: Johnny Watpole, fellas.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know where he still lives or nothing.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's got arthritis, a bad old hip.
[SPEAKER_03]: Rockford, we went over to see him five or six years ago.
[SPEAKER_02]: He played first base for you sometime, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_03]: Right, right.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was just before.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who would be short-stepping that line before Applin?
[SPEAKER_03]: Sissel.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Bill Sissel.
[SPEAKER_02]: You remember Bill?
[SPEAKER_02]: Chalmers, Williams.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a tragic life.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did Bill Hunterfield play over there?
[SPEAKER_02]: You know Hunterfield?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was there ahead of me.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was second baseman.
[SPEAKER_03]: And, uh, what was that boy's name?
[SPEAKER_03]: Billy Camp.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He went to Cleveland for, uh... That big first baseman.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was that big first baseman's name?
[SPEAKER_03]: Big, tall... Arthur Great Shires.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ooh, not that far.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had that big hunk of the back.
[SPEAKER_03]: See, he was with us in Washington.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had his car.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who's this now?
[SPEAKER_03]: Art Shires.
[SPEAKER_03]: He bought him a car on the wheels.
[SPEAKER_03]: Fender wheels back then, they had them covered.
[SPEAKER_03]: Had Art the Great Shires on the trunk.
[SPEAKER_03]: Had Art the Great Shires.
[SPEAKER_03]: He bought him a trunk for traveling.
[SPEAKER_03]: We wanted suitcases, put a suit of clothes in it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh no, that wasn't good enough for him.
[SPEAKER_03]: He got a red, white, and blue trunk.
[SPEAKER_03]: Had it painted red, white, and blue.
[SPEAKER_03]: It had on that Art the Great Shires.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was he as conceited as he sounded?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: He wasn't that conceited.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was mostly show.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a pretty good fighter, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_02]: A boxer, didn't he take on some?
[SPEAKER_03]: I know he took on Trafton and someone else.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know what kind of fighter he was.
[SPEAKER_03]: I remember in the Sporty News seeing some stories about him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I know he hit Lena Blackburn in the eye.
[SPEAKER_03]: I know that.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was his manager in baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: Wasn't the right person to hit.
[SPEAKER_03]: Gave him a bad eye.
[SPEAKER_02]: He must have been kind of hard to manage though, I would think, Sharns.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've had it pretty tough physically, as far as my wife's concerned, not me.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was hard on her, though, this blindness, and these three pacemakers.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's been mighty bad.
[SPEAKER_03]: She's been a good gal, though.
[SPEAKER_03]: She's stuck with me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I certainly admire you, the way you've handled all this.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, you know what I always tell people?
[SPEAKER_02]: I've got two good arms.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've got two legs, I can get about, and I'm all right.
[SPEAKER_02]: I can see how you're an inspiration to those kids.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've got two good arms and two good legs.
[SPEAKER_02]: As long as I can get about, and my dog, I can go all right.
[SPEAKER_02]: I can see how you are.
[SPEAKER_03]: I can go anywhere I want to go with this dog.
[SPEAKER_02]: I can see how you'd mean so much to those kids, though.
[SPEAKER_02]: You don't know how much they meant to me.
[SPEAKER_03]: They asked me one time, they said, Papa Jack, will you please tell us something?
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, what is it?
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, well, mix a little red, a little yellow.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, yeah, but we haven't ever seen red.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, that's the truth you have now.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, no.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, well, I think they were sweet little gals.
[SPEAKER_03]: Some of them, one from Texas, one from just out of Chicago.
[SPEAKER_03]: What's the word of that prison?
[SPEAKER_02]: Jodiette.
[SPEAKER_03]: And one from Texas, and one from Illinois, and one from Connecticut.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, they were scattered.
[SPEAKER_03]: Florida, they were scattered.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you know Moose Solders?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did I?
[SPEAKER_03]: Played with him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: Moose was with us out in spring training.
[SPEAKER_02]: That crazy accident he had.
[SPEAKER_03]: What happened to him?
[SPEAKER_03]: I never have heard.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, well, he was 41, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know if he's with the White Sox in or not.
[SPEAKER_02]: No?
[SPEAKER_02]: He'd left us.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, well, Boston or St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_03]: I knew he lost his sight, but how?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was just during, he was just playing shortstop in infield practice.
[SPEAKER_02]: He wasn't outfield, but just fooling around playing infield.
[SPEAKER_02]: And a ground ball took a bad hop, hit him in the forehead.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he began having dizzy spells.
[SPEAKER_02]: And it took about eight or nine years, but he finally was lost to all this.
[SPEAKER_02]: Looks like both his eyes are in a crazy accident like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: You never know.
[SPEAKER_03]: I lost sight of my right one, like I said, in 40.
[SPEAKER_02]: How was it for those years?
[SPEAKER_02]: Could you see much at all?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, my left eye was good.
[SPEAKER_03]: But every time I stick my head in the car or anything, I'd turn to the right.
[SPEAKER_03]: And when I did, pow, I'd bop my head.
[SPEAKER_03]: I called myself Naughty Head.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had knots all over my head, bumping things.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was tough on the little boy.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had a little boy, we got a little boy on the top, a little on the
[SPEAKER_03]: adopted boy.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I had to go to him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I couldn't say, see son.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd say, feel.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd come up to me and say, feel daddy, feel this daddy.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, that got next to you.
[SPEAKER_03]: Everything he'd come to me, he wouldn't ever say, see daddy.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd say, feel daddy, feel this daddy, feel this daddy, feel that.
[SPEAKER_03]: But we got along all right.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was fine.
[SPEAKER_02]: What about baseball?
[SPEAKER_02]: What was your greatest day?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you have a great day that extends out?
[SPEAKER_02]: A thrill?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, we played Boston one day, and you know Joe Cashman, the sports writer over there?
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess I heard of him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had a home run, two doubles, and a single, and the headlines in the paper, old box score, his name was White Sox, I mean the Red Sox were hazed.
[SPEAKER_03]: I thought that was pretty good, and I had 15, let me see how many chances did
[SPEAKER_03]: 34 or 32 chances was a record in two games out at the second base.
[SPEAKER_03]: 30-something, 32.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was 18 one day and 15 the next one.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was 33, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_03]: I think it was in two games without an error.
[SPEAKER_03]: In two games.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know that Boston ballpark way back then, the infield was kind of slow.
[SPEAKER_03]: You could go a long ways for a ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, it wouldn't do like they do today, boop, boop, boop, and go on through.
[SPEAKER_03]: It bounced slow.
[SPEAKER_03]: But that was a record at that time.
[SPEAKER_03]: At least they put it in the paper that he was.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about tough pitchers to hit?
[SPEAKER_02]: You said Feller was an easy one.
[SPEAKER_03]: Not easy, none of them easy.
[SPEAKER_03]: None of them up there easy.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I didn't say he was easy.
[SPEAKER_03]: None of them easy, but I just had luck with him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Harder, I think, was the toughest.
[SPEAKER_03]: Mel Harder was a good pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: Gomez was pretty tough.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: I just wouldn't, I wouldn't, I wouldn't.
[SPEAKER_03]: all good.
[SPEAKER_03]: You didn't go at the bat.
[SPEAKER_03]: When you got in the big, you didn't see a bad pitcher there.
[SPEAKER_03]: They were all good.
[SPEAKER_03]: You had to be good to stay up there.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the big difference that I see in today's baseball and that, they had better pitching.
[SPEAKER_03]: But when a pitcher went out on that mound, he knew he had to go nine innings.
[SPEAKER_03]: He didn't have somebody come in the fifth or sixth inning to help him know he was going to get a reliever because he didn't have a two on the ball club.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now seventh and eighth inning, they might call a reliever in.
[SPEAKER_03]: left-hander and a right-hander, they'd have them in the ball club.
[SPEAKER_03]: Old boy came by to see me two years ago, I hadn't seen him since he got out of baseball, and he pitched a no-hit game one day there with White Sox.
[SPEAKER_03]: You remember Bobby Burke?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: B-U-R-K-E?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: He came by to see me, he'd been down to Florida.
[SPEAKER_03]: I have a lot of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: John Schulte, remember John Schulte beat the Yankees?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a coach with me.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right, with the A's.
[SPEAKER_03]: He came by to see me.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a John Shue team.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did Bill Dietrich pitch a no-hitter with the White Sox?
[SPEAKER_03]: Think he did.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bill Bullfrog, we used to call him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Little big guy.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, everybody had a nickname.
[SPEAKER_02]: Vernon Kennedy?
[SPEAKER_03]: Vernon Kennedy, we used to call him the professor.
[SPEAKER_02]: You had a lot of no-hitters in that team.
[SPEAKER_03]: We had that.
[SPEAKER_03]: In the second division.
[SPEAKER_03]: We'd always call him that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Everybody had a nickname in baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, Lord, it was something.
[SPEAKER_03]: Let's see, I'm trying to think.
[SPEAKER_03]: John Rigney came by to see me one day.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was over at Maplesville.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he saw that sign over there, Clanton.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had two fellas who said, I'm going by Clanton.
[SPEAKER_03]: I want to see my buddy.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know, he married a Comiskey girl.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he came by to see me.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever meet the old Comiskey?
[SPEAKER_02]: Mr. Comiskey?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, Charles.
[SPEAKER_03]: Not the old man.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I never did meet him.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was before.
[SPEAKER_03]: Lou Comiskey.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, he was in Grabner, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was most of your business with Grabner when contract time came?
[SPEAKER_03]: I talked with Mr. Comiskey, Mr. Lou Comiskey, most of the time.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think Grabner had the final say.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think he had the final say grabbing her.
[SPEAKER_02]: How was Lou Comiskey to deal with?
[SPEAKER_02]: Was he pretty good?
[SPEAKER_02]: Pretty good, but... Did you ever hold out at all?
[SPEAKER_03]: I was holding out all the time.
[SPEAKER_03]: Never did get more money either.
[SPEAKER_03]: Always holding out, didn't get much money.
[SPEAKER_03]: But the year that I got my best salary was the year that my wife went through the records.
[SPEAKER_03]: Only hit .229.
[SPEAKER_03]: Her batting average
[SPEAKER_03]: had 79 runs batted and led, the man that led the league in hitting, I batted in more runs than he did.
[SPEAKER_03]: I finished second.
[SPEAKER_03]: Luke who?
[SPEAKER_02]: Appling?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, Luke didn't end, who's that left-hander with, the boy played shortstop with Washington then, but not Buddy Lewis, what's that other one?
[SPEAKER_03]: Cecil Travis?
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the guy.
[SPEAKER_03]: Travis was the man that led the league and I had batted in more runs and fielded second that year behind Charlie Gerringer.
[SPEAKER_03]: Charlie was the first average.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I had more chances than he did.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I had, we had more double plays, I think, that year than they did, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, my wife got the thing down and sent it in to Mr. Comiskey and told him, said, well, said, if we're not worth more now, we never will be worth more.
[SPEAKER_03]: So here's the averages.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he wrote a big article about it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think you got it there, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_03]: About, told Miss Ryan, and I said, Miss Ryan, you better give him
[SPEAKER_03]: good contract cause that boy's got us here now.
[SPEAKER_03]: I used to use my automobile business and that's 1929.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean I hit 229 that year.
[SPEAKER_03]: So to me, I have always said this, ever since I've been, all the time I was in baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's not the average, it's what you can do, it's not always just the average, it's the runs batted in.
[SPEAKER_03]: Cause the ones that cross that place are the ones that count.
[SPEAKER_03]: And the ones that you keep from going in there with your feeling is a great help to the pitchers too.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: Like Ted Lyons used to say, if you've got credit, Billy Webb won.
[SPEAKER_03]: You remember Billy Webb, the coach?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't remember him, no.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, Jack, if you've got credit for the runs that you saved from going across the plate, he said you'd hit 300 every year.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think runs batted in isn't always too good an indicator, because we're up in the Cincinnati area there, and you hear an awful lot about Johnny Bench.
[SPEAKER_02]: It seems to me Bench leaves an awful lot of men on base.
[SPEAKER_02]: He drives in a lot.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he comes up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's always men on base.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he comes up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it depends on where you hit the batting order.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he comes up with all these good hitters.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he's got a lot of chances.
[SPEAKER_02]: They're on base.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he leaves a lot of men on base.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: But we don't hear about that.
[SPEAKER_03]: I agree with you.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: They don't hear about the runs that you keep coming in by your defensive play.
[SPEAKER_03]: You don't get credit for that.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've always said there should be some way of scoring that your defense should count in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just the pure fielding itself is not
[SPEAKER_02]: too complete, because it doesn't give any evidence of range.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some people cover more ground, they're going to make more errors.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's exactly right.
[SPEAKER_02]: But they have more chances.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's hard to do, though.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know what old Sam Jones told them, told the newspaper men right after I quit?
[SPEAKER_02]: What's that?
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, if I was playing baseball, and I was in the World Series, had one ball to be hit, and I always took that as a great compliment, I'd always want to hit the Jackie Hay.
[SPEAKER_03]: Had one ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: to be here and get them out.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd always wanted to be here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, wasn't that a compliment?
[SPEAKER_03]: From a sad Sam Jones.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did you do in the off-season in those days?
[SPEAKER_02]: Hunt.
[SPEAKER_03]: You mean before I was married?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, hunt.
[SPEAKER_03]: Walked a lot.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did a lot of walking.
[SPEAKER_03]: Used to have a camp down on the river.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's mighty up and down, hilly down there.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I'd go down there about two or three weeks before I'd go to spring training.
[SPEAKER_03]: They always want to know how I came to spring training in such good shape.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd run up down those hills out there when I got out of spring training.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think there's another thing that, now this may not be exactly right, but I think spring training is too short.
[SPEAKER_03]: If you want to get yourself in good shape in spring training,
[SPEAKER_03]: you don't have trouble with all these things during the season about me and folks being crippled and everything.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now that's what Dykes used to preach too.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said you get yourself in spring training, get yourself in good physical condition in spring training, you won't have trouble during the season with your arms and your legs and things.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that sounds reasonable.
[SPEAKER_02]: Of course Eddie Roush, Eddie Roush, he'd never go to spring training.
[SPEAKER_03]: I played exhibition games against him, against Eddie Roush.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's a long time ago.
[SPEAKER_03]: You remember old
[SPEAKER_03]: Mr. John McGraw?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I never saw him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I saw him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I played against him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, he was manager of the Giants then.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Andy Cohen, they all hollered in the stand, Ice Cream Cohen.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was from Alabama.
[SPEAKER_02]: I just interviewed a chap two days or three days ago, played quite a while under McGraw.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's Kent Greenfield up in Guthrie, Kentucky.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a pitcher for the Giants.
[SPEAKER_02]: I remember that name, Greenfield.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: He played about four or five years.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you remember a fellow, Big Ed Morris?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a Red Sox pitcher, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_03]: Reliefer.
[SPEAKER_03]: Way back then.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tell me about him.
[SPEAKER_02]: And who else did he have?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was killed in a bar room accident.
[SPEAKER_03]: Sure was.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who was that long-legged fellow?
[SPEAKER_03]: Ken Williams!
[SPEAKER_03]: I saw him do the funnest thing I've ever seen a ball player do.
[SPEAKER_03]: Pitcher was trying to walk him, throw three balls outside, and started to throw the fourth one out, and he reached out and he popped it up to the end.
[SPEAKER_02]: Pop it up to the end, Bill.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ken Williams.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a great hitter, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_03]: Ken Williams.
[SPEAKER_03]: LeBron's for years.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was with Boston Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Phil Tope was the first baseman.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, when I first began playing baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Rigney.
[SPEAKER_03]: Rigney was the infielder.
[SPEAKER_03]: And, oh, there was Rabbit Warsler.
[SPEAKER_03]: And a man named, who was that boy that played there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Rawlings, Red Rawlings.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ira Flagstaff.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ira Flagstaff.
[SPEAKER_02]: Good gracious.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was there a Boston outfielder named Skerritt?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes sir, Russ Skerritt.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes sir, he was a good one.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think he's from Florida, I'm not sure, but he was a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had one great year, or a good year, and then he seemed to disappear.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right, I don't know what happened to that boy.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about David Dale Alexander?
[SPEAKER_02]: He played first base.
[SPEAKER_03]: Stop.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's in Greenville, Tennessee.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's a good boy, I'll tell you that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ain't he a little big old man?
[SPEAKER_03]: We used to holler at him from the bench all the time.
[SPEAKER_03]: Why don't you go out and drink a beer and take a cold?
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the way he talked.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, you go drink a beer and take a cold.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you think he would be easy to interview or like to be interviewed?
[SPEAKER_02]: I think he would.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, he's back around the days of Rudy York, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_02]: That was before then.
[SPEAKER_02]: He won the American League bag title at 32.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, he could hit that ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: He could hit that ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: Dave was a good boy.
[SPEAKER_03]: But you know, ballplayers always kid each other.
[SPEAKER_03]: Shoot.
[SPEAKER_03]: Just like one time I came to Baton, Washington.
[SPEAKER_03]: Nick hollered at me, and they got a Dixie Cafe in town.
[SPEAKER_03]: Nick hollered at me, said, told me before that he came through here playing exhibition game, he signed a check down there and left it for me.
[SPEAKER_03]: to pay at the Dixie Cafe, and he hollered at me when I'd go to bed, hey, Jackie, you pay that bill at the Dixie Cafe?
[SPEAKER_03]: When I was traded over to Washington, he was always yelling things.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bib Falk, you remember Bib Falk?
[SPEAKER_03]: Sure.
[SPEAKER_03]: I filled her.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bib Augustus Falk.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had a ring.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had a new car, and I bumped into a fireplug.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, ha-ha, be deep, honey, huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: You kidding me, said I was holding a girl, and my arm ran into a tree.
[SPEAKER_03]: They always try to get something on you that they yelled at you, if they make it up.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's like Sam Jones used to call Bing Miller, but we quit doing that.
[SPEAKER_03]: He used to call him Uncle Tom, called us the Dark Era.
[SPEAKER_03]: He even called Toe Fletcher, he used to burn us out.
[SPEAKER_03]: Q's Fletcher burned us out.
[SPEAKER_03]: You remember Art Fletcher?
[SPEAKER_03]: Fletcher?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, for years.
[SPEAKER_03]: He could steal signs.
[SPEAKER_03]: And we had a boy with us, let me tell you about it.
[SPEAKER_03]: He could get signs from those pitches.
[SPEAKER_03]: Mervin Shea?
[SPEAKER_03]: Catcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was first base coach.
[SPEAKER_03]: He didn't use that picture, but he moved his hand just like Jimmy Dishon.
[SPEAKER_03]: Jimmy Dishon came to here.
[SPEAKER_03]: Remember Tommy Bridges?
[SPEAKER_03]: If Tommy Bridges went way up like that, it was a curveball.
[SPEAKER_02]: If he'd go short, he really gave it away.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, they watch him, I'm telling you, they watch him like a hawk watching a chicken.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were there any spitball pitchers still around when you came up there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: John Packers Quinn, that fellow Mitchell was with Cleveland, and there's a fellow named, uh... Kovaleski was gone then, huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: Kovaleski was gone.
[SPEAKER_03]: Red Faber.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I played behind Red Faber, and I was the second base, and some fellow hit a little soft ground ball right after I joined the club.
[SPEAKER_03]: Nobody told me about it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I caught that ball and started throwing it to the first and threw it up the upper deck of the stand.
[SPEAKER_03]: I caught that slick spot.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do it right straight up.
[SPEAKER_03]: From then on, everyone was playing.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, Jack, I'm going to get you a handful of dirt every time.
[SPEAKER_03]: Those balls, so I got to get me a handful of dirt.
[SPEAKER_03]: When you catch a spit ball, is it that time?
[SPEAKER_03]: It might take too long here now.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's all right.
[SPEAKER_02]: We're having a great time in the water.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's fun.
[SPEAKER_02]: Here you are.
[SPEAKER_03]: Thank you, ma'am.
[SPEAKER_02]: Thank you, sweetie.
[SPEAKER_02]: Thank you.
[SPEAKER_02]: George Uley told me about it.
[SPEAKER_03]: One of the greatest pitchers of all times, I always thought.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you bat against him?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: And a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think he's proud of his hitting and his pitching.
[SPEAKER_03]: Man, he was a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: He could hit that ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd have been a great outfielder.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he was telling me about the 1920 World Series when the Indians were playing the Dodgers and Burley Grimes as a football pitcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: Right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I hit against Burley Grimes in spring, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: They used to spot that Brooklyn second baseman Jake Kilduff.
[SPEAKER_02]: Every so often, reach down and grab some dirt.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, the spitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that's why I said, on every pitch, I'd get dirt.
[SPEAKER_03]: If I just got it on the spitter, they'd know that's when it was coming.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I'd reach down and get some on every pitch.
[SPEAKER_03]: Fastball, curveball.
[SPEAKER_02]: You knew when the spitter was coming from there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Old Red Faber was a sight.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I could see him slopping all over that.
[SPEAKER_02]: He used this old slip rail.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he slopped when he didn't throw the spitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just throw the batter off.
[SPEAKER_02]: Right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just give the impression.
[SPEAKER_03]: Right, right.
[SPEAKER_02]: You couldn't do it every time.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, we had a way of telling them when he was going, you see what the catcher called for, where he's going.
[SPEAKER_03]: We would, we always went by the catcher signs.
[SPEAKER_03]: And what the catcher called for is what we played for.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's where you got to play out there on your toes.
[SPEAKER_03]: And you'd always, I've always said, and I still believe, that if you're sitting in the stand and you watch your outfielders, you don't even have to look at that picture.
[SPEAKER_03]: You can tell when that pitcher throws the ball by the outfielders coming up on the toes, getting ready to go.
[SPEAKER_03]: Infielders getting up on the toes, getting ready to go.
[SPEAKER_03]: You can tell when that ball is being thrown.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, if you're just a spectator, you just notice that at some ball game.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, you see outfielders.
[SPEAKER_03]: One of the hustling outfielders are the ones that come up and get ready to go.
[SPEAKER_03]: If you're up and ready to go, you've got to start on them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Can they see from out in the field the signals very well?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_03]: You mean out in the outfield?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, they can't tell.
[SPEAKER_03]: Sometimes infielders give them signals.
[SPEAKER_03]: They have some sign to give to them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Or a hand behind the back, a hand on the shoulder, or something.
[SPEAKER_03]: Let them know what's going to be pitched.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I don't think that's too much help to an outfielder.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because before the ball games, you go over the lineup, and you know about which way you want to play them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Which way the manager wants you to play them, I should say.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then, but now I think it's where you want to play them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Players run the game now.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's what DeRosa said.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: DeRosa said, players run the game.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, the manager's got a chance.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, the ball players make more money than the manager.
[SPEAKER_03]: So they tell us what to do.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you back up when Ruth came to bat?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I'd get back on the edge of the grass.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, on the edge of the grass.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wouldn't get out now.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd feel like I'd get back on the edge.
[SPEAKER_03]: And we never pulled that big shift around like they used to pull.
[SPEAKER_02]: Could Ruth hit the left field at all, or didn't he ever?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: I know one thing.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd hit some of the highest ones he's ever hit.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ooh, you'd go round and round and round before we'd come down.
[SPEAKER_03]: And in Comiskey Park, if the wind's blowing just right, if that ball would get above the stands, if you take the winds coming from that direction,
[SPEAKER_03]: It blows back in the fire.
[SPEAKER_03]: If you didn't stay with it, you wouldn't get it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Lots of times.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've seen balls that you sweat are going to be foul balls, and they land fire.
[SPEAKER_03]: But you always, before they, between innings, we did, all the time, look back to see what our flag was doing.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because if the wind changes, comes off of that lake, you can change your ball game right quick.
[SPEAKER_02]: What a fascinating career it's been.
[SPEAKER_02]: Thanks, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had a lot of fun.
[SPEAKER_03]: I loved it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't just didn't play for the money because we didn't get much money but I played for the fun and I loved all the ball players and I hope they loved me.
[SPEAKER_02]: What would you do in the uh off the field as recreation or entertainment?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh when Dykes got to be manager he let's go play golf.
[SPEAKER_03]: Up until then, the managers wouldn't let you play golf.
[SPEAKER_03]: They were afraid you'd interfere with your swing at baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: But Dax is so crazy about golf, he lets you play.
[SPEAKER_03]: We didn't even have a tournament between the White Sox and the Cubs golf tournament.
[SPEAKER_03]: And some of the boys would go to racetrack.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never cared much about it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't bet on them.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd go out there and watch a lot of them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Off season.
[SPEAKER_02]: race track did he?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, he's afraid, I think he's kind of afraid of getting mixed up with the cameras.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't quote this Bill Sissel, that's what he did.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't understand it for a while.
[SPEAKER_02]: I knew you were going to mention that name.
[SPEAKER_02]: Maybe just tell me about him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Stevenson or somebody.
[SPEAKER_02]: Or maybe it was Greenfield.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was over there with Stevie.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was over there with the Cub.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, he could hit that ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: And the funny, the strangest thing, now as long as he played ball, and as smart as he was, I can't never did understand why when he went on to St. Louis Browns he'd always make them take a strike.
[SPEAKER_03]: He didn't go up to play, they had to take a strike.
[SPEAKER_03]: Dick Kaufman, a boy from up here in North Alabama, pull a good one on him though.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, Hornsby made a rule, said no smoking and no newspapers in the clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_03]: So they went to Yankee Stadium and they got a big hall outside the clubhouse door there.
[SPEAKER_03]: All the trunks were lined up out there.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said one day, once we came in, he caught me sitting out there, just had a jockstrap on, had a cigarette, and a newspaper in his hand.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, well, you said not in the clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, I'm sitting out here now.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he blew up, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: I've asked a number of people about that.
[SPEAKER_02]: He seems to be such a hard man to get on with, from what I read.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I never played under him.
[SPEAKER_03]: But off of the field, I mean, in an opposing team, I was found to be clean and a good fellow.
[SPEAKER_03]: But of course, that was after his playing days, most of when I was with him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I saw him play when he was with the Johnson, somebody way back.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was just a kid coming up in 27.
[SPEAKER_03]: Travis Jackson, he was a shortstop for the Johnson.
[SPEAKER_03]: Freddie Lindstrom, Bill Terry was the first baseman.
[SPEAKER_03]: Hugh Crites.
[SPEAKER_03]: Andy Cohen was the second baby, and old Big Shanny Hogan was one of the catchers.
[SPEAKER_03]: And like you said, Eddie Rouse.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you play against George Sisler at all when he was still with the Browns?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: George Sisler came to the Washington Club.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, did he?
[SPEAKER_03]: He had sinus trouble when he came to us.
[SPEAKER_03]: He and Judge split first base.
[SPEAKER_03]: One played one for a while, and the other one would play when they were both going out.
[SPEAKER_03]: Remember George had sinus trouble?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he had eye trouble one year.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was sinus.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's why he had to quit.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then he came back and hit 400 or something.
[SPEAKER_03]: He is a fine, he's a perfect gentleman, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know these players when you're on the club with them, how they live off the field and how they live on the field.
[SPEAKER_03]: Somebody drank a beer once in a while, ain't nothing wrong with that.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's a pretty close camaraderie and spirit among them.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think so.
[SPEAKER_02]: When you're traveling the trains and roads.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh yes, oh yes.
[SPEAKER_03]: You got one group that'll play some kind of cards and another group will play something else or something else.
[SPEAKER_02]: Play gin rummy.
[SPEAKER_02]: You get tired of each other's presence?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, no, don't do that.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: And when they go out to go in a place at night, see we play day ball all the time, most of the time.
[SPEAKER_03]: When you got to go in a place at night, it's two or three, I'll be together.
[SPEAKER_03]: If you ever saw one, Lone Wolf and all.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you ever play night ball?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: One of the first, second, first game, I think, we missed the proper second.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, they had lights.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's when I broke, beat Feller with that long hit.
[SPEAKER_03]: I got two of the three hits that I made that night.
[SPEAKER_03]: We beat him one another.
[SPEAKER_03]: Were you in that opening?
[SPEAKER_03]: Ten hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he pitch opening day in 1940?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I don't think.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, not in 1940, because 1940's when I left.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was spring training.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's when you got hit.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's when I started having my troubles.
[SPEAKER_03]: He opened the season that year with a no-hitter against the White Sox.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, yes.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I wasn't there then.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was in the hospital.
[SPEAKER_03]: because they sent me right on back, right to the doctor and to the hospital.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well this is, I think I've taken enough of your time here.
[SPEAKER_03]: You got what you wanted, that's what I want you to have.
[SPEAKER_03]: I sure do.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's been a, oh I suppose I go on for a long time talking baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh those players back then talk about all of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know the one that I saw put on the greatest exhibition of hitting that ever was?
[SPEAKER_02]: Who's that?
[SPEAKER_03]: was a boy from out in Texas named, oh lord, he was a first baseman.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'll tell you his name.
[SPEAKER_03]: But the first three times he came to bat, after he'd been with the White Sox about a month or two, they put him in there, he hit the first three times home runs in the left field stand, line drive.
[SPEAKER_03]: And the fourth time, the ball hit the wall like that much going in.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Merv Connors.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a first baseman from Texas, from the Texas league.
[SPEAKER_03]: They found out about the league, he couldn't hit a curveball.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know where he wound up?
[SPEAKER_03]: Back in Texas.
[SPEAKER_03]: He got his cup of coffee and left.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a great moment, though.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had a great day.
[SPEAKER_02]: They couldn't teach him to hit the curve.
[SPEAKER_03]: He couldn't hit the curve.
[SPEAKER_03]: In big league baseball, what I found, if you had an outstanding weakness, you could not correct it yourself, might as well come on back home.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because those pitches, they knew where that ball was going.
[SPEAKER_03]: And if you had an outstanding weakness,
[SPEAKER_03]: But it went around over the league, and they all knew about it, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know how it got around with trading players like that, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's one way of looking at it.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's like Al Denokker, you used to pitch from down there.
[SPEAKER_03]: One of the Detroit players finally came to our club.
[SPEAKER_03]: We couldn't hit him with a paddle.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, all right.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, now what you do from now on?
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, you look at his foot when you get ready to hit.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, don't look up there for that ball to come.
[SPEAKER_03]: Look down there where he throws it.
[SPEAKER_03]: And some of them got hit pretty good.
[SPEAKER_03]: See, when he comes from there, if you're looking up where you look at a regular pitcher, that ball comes up like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: But if you're looking at that ball, you follow it all the way up there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: You follow the ball all the way up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Eldon Auker.
[SPEAKER_02]: I saw him pitch a number of times, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tommy Bridges, Eldon Auker, Schubarro.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think Bridges and Auker both were from Tennessee.
[SPEAKER_02]: Hawker lives up in Boston now, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's deceased now.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right, he's from up in Nashville.
[SPEAKER_02]: I came through there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was going to see Red Lucas and Johnny Gooch in Nashville.
[SPEAKER_03]: Lord, if you see Red Lucas, tell him Jack Hayes said hello.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he wasn't home.
[SPEAKER_03]: You what?
[SPEAKER_02]: I went to his house.
[SPEAKER_02]: Fred Lucas?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a good pinch hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he was another good pinch hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ted Lyons was a good hitting pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: Charlie Ruffing was a good hitting pitcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: I wound up talking to Johnny Gill.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever know Johnny Gill?
[SPEAKER_03]: I knew of him.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was all.
[SPEAKER_03]: Johnny had to leave.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't have too big a career up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: But Gooch was dead and Lucas wasn't home, so I didn't do much in Nashville.
[SPEAKER_03]: Johnny Gooch was.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was deceased.
[SPEAKER_02]: There was no Johnny Gooch.
[SPEAKER_02]: I knew Charlie Gooch.
[SPEAKER_02]: About last fall, I believe.
[SPEAKER_02]: Charlie Gooch was the third baseman in Washington, way back.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we came down through, didn't get to see anybody in Birmingham, because we had Walker Boys.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, Dick Spud Davis up there, isn't there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, Spud Davis had an operation.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was in the hospital.
[SPEAKER_03]: Had three of them, Sports Hall of Famers, in that hospital at one time.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was there, Spud Davis was there, and a fellow named Snit Snyder, who was a track star, we'd give him off and went to the hospital.
[SPEAKER_03]: They said we all had a reunion, but it wasn't a happy one.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ben Chapman, I guess, is up in Birmingham.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, old chap is right up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've got a book here with all the baseball addresses.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was listed in Selma, but I guess... Well, he's moved back to Birmingham.
[SPEAKER_03]: I see Ben all lots.
[SPEAKER_03]: And saw him up there at the Sports Hall of Fame dinner?
[SPEAKER_03]: I thought he'd be a good interview subject.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, he can give you some stuff.
[SPEAKER_03]: He sure can.
[SPEAKER_03]: Wasn't that night up there at the Sports Hall of Fame dinner?
[SPEAKER_03]: They showed a picture up there.
[SPEAKER_03]: We all had a picture of him trying to break up a double play.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had the ball, and I'd already thrown the ball, and I was looking at the first base to see who called him out.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, gentlemen, where were you all that time?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a tough competitor, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ben was a good ball player.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a hustling ball player.
[SPEAKER_03]: When he cuts you or kicked you, he didn't mean it for mischief.
[SPEAKER_03]: He meant it to win the ball game.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's what he's trying to do now.
[SPEAKER_03]: He wasn't like Jacob Powell, he wouldn't grab you around the legs.
[SPEAKER_03]: But you talking about people coming off the beach, Booker Harris and all of them, every one of them along the beach came running off there, wanted to cut one of that umpire, man, they got caught.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never did throw the ball to first.
[SPEAKER_03]: He called him out.
[SPEAKER_03]: Fred Sington.
[SPEAKER_03]: Birmingham.
[SPEAKER_03]: Good boy.
[SPEAKER_03]: Fine fella.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he's a
[SPEAKER_03]: leader in Birmingham and everything that comes up with that.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's one of the civic leaders.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, he is.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think he's going to have a football game or a bowl game.
[SPEAKER_02]: I believe I saw something in the paper about that.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's heading up the committee.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I'll sign this off now.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've been talking with Mr. Hayes here in his home in Clanton on August 5, 1977.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's been a delightful interview.
[SPEAKER_02]: Thank you very much.
[SPEAKER_02]: Thank you, sir.
[SPEAKER_02]: Very good.
[SPEAKER_01]: OK, now for a little bit of comment on the interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm talking from the Colony Motel in Columbus, Georgia, Tuesday afternoon at 5.30, 1977.
[SPEAKER_01]: Rita's been sick all day.
[SPEAKER_01]: We were going to leave Columbus today, but we stayed out another day.
[SPEAKER_01]: I hope that she'll feel better for tomorrow.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I haven't had a chance to comment on the Hayes tape of Friday or the Wells tape of Saturday.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought I'd use up the rest of the space here.
[SPEAKER_01]: We drove from Tuscaloosa to Montgomery on Friday.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it's about 100 miles.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's Friday, August 5, I think it is.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's about 100 miles.
[SPEAKER_01]: Clanton's about halfway in between, a little bit off to the east.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we drove down to Maplesville and over to Clanton.
[SPEAKER_01]: from there, about 20 miles, and then came on in on Route 65 to Montgomery by late afternoon, mid-afternoon.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had the 10.30 appointment, but there was a railroad tie-up in Maplesville, and the railroad train blocked the road there for about half an hour.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I found another way around and arrived, going back to the main road, down a little bit, over on the country road, back on the country road, hit the road to climb it that way, and arrived around 11 o'clock, about a half hour later.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we talked about 12, 15 or so.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was, as this tape shows, around an hour and 20 minutes, maybe an hour and 15 minutes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Hayes is a pretty tall man, 6 feet 1 or so.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's well built.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's thin and gray-haired, looks just like you'd expect him from his pictures.
[SPEAKER_01]: as his sixth seeing my dog, Angel, with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was quite playful and joyful, and I knocked Reed over when she came in to pick me up later.
[SPEAKER_01]: They went for a tour of the town, Reed and Kathy, because there was nothing for them to do, and they didn't want to be in the interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I told them to come back in about an hour, and they did.
[SPEAKER_01]: They came back earlier, I guess, just sat under the shade of the trees, because it was a very hot day, driving around even hotter.
[SPEAKER_01]: He just came back and sat under the shade of the Hayes trees.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Mrs. Hayes welcomed me.
[SPEAKER_01]: She was a pleasant woman from South Alabama.
[SPEAKER_01]: Married him at 34, I guess, towards the end of his career, middle of his career.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then at 36, I forgot much, of course, the blindness
[SPEAKER_01]: He sent it in 40s.
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't have too many years without disability.
[SPEAKER_01]: But she has carried on very well.
[SPEAKER_01]: As he said in one of the parts of the tape, he has adjusted to this, but it's been pretty rough on her since she has to take care of them quite a bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: She was a little bit nervous about the interview and kept saying that she couldn't have them in, Rita and Kathy, for a tea or something, because she was so busy dealing with something.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can tell, she was a little excited about all of this.
[SPEAKER_01]: Once we got going, she left us and was here again until toward the end.
[SPEAKER_01]: Once the guys went out again.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a remarkable man.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's handled this very well.
[SPEAKER_01]: He spoke about the blind children over it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Clanton or other places that he has worked with and have been an inspiration.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they have been to him, but of course, I said, well, she's meant to them, and he turns around and is very gracious and modest.
[SPEAKER_01]: Good memory, good mind.
[SPEAKER_01]: He sat there kind of on the edge of his chair holding a noosh of the dog, who was
[SPEAKER_01]: sitting by the side of the table there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Occasionally he would get up and thrash around and he'd order an angel to sit down again.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he picked up the things very quickly.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mr. Hayes, he picked up the questions and recalled names and recalled stories very well.
[SPEAKER_01]: Rather, I don't know, I thought he might
[SPEAKER_01]: Maybe the blindness, since his life has been somewhat inactive since then, sharpened his recollections of the days before.
[SPEAKER_01]: At any rate, it was a good interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's quite a bit said there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought it went quite well.
[SPEAKER_01]: I forgot a little bit about, I think, some of the surrounding circumstances and obstacles several days ago.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know the house was a very nice ranch-style house.
[SPEAKER_01]: driveway leading into the back there, air-conditioned, very nice furniture around.
[SPEAKER_01]: He gave me one of those miniature bats.
[SPEAKER_01]: There were no pictures, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or there were scrapbooks and pictures which were put away, and she didn't want to get them out.
[SPEAKER_01]: He asked her a couple times to get some pictures out, but she didn't have the time for it or didn't know where they were, so I didn't get any pictures at all.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got an autograph for the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: But this has been a bad trip for pictures.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm a riddle today.
[SPEAKER_01]: I have no pictures.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wells had a few pictures on the wall, but nothing I could photograph or nothing to give me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joey Sewell didn't have much.
[SPEAKER_01]: Rick Stevenson was the best one I had.
[SPEAKER_01]: I haven't got much of anybody else.
[SPEAKER_01]: I may not have any more interviews.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boy, this thing's developing.
[SPEAKER_01]: I may have to hustle right back home.
[SPEAKER_01]: bypass Atlanta.
[SPEAKER_01]: I do have an interview scheduled for Atlanta tonight, which I'm going to have to call and cancel because we're not in Atlanta tonight.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's Bobby Smith, the old pitcher, who I spoke to last night.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was quite looking forward to this.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I said I just have to tell him he can't be there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Maybe he'll have some pictures if I do get to see him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I hope so.
[SPEAKER_01]: We left the Hayes home there.
[SPEAKER_01]: She brought in a glass of water.
[SPEAKER_01]: during the interview and brought him a glass of water.
[SPEAKER_01]: And none of these interviews has anybody brought me any beer or anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Lemonade and gills, most times they don't bring me anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or there hasn't been occasion to.
[SPEAKER_01]: No reason for it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it's been something rather plain.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've been somewhat amused by that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so we wanted to, we came back around 12 o'clock, knocked on the door, came in, and the angel practically knocked her over.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we chatted a little while.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mrs. Hayes showed us some of the mementos.
[SPEAKER_01]: One thing that he came up with was his first helmet that he wore in 1940, a kind of a radio-operated earplugs type of thing strapped over the head.
[SPEAKER_01]: This was after he lost the vision in his right eye.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was trying to play ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he claims he was the first player ever to wear a helmet.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he got up seated in a chair there, holding the helmet.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I snapped a picture of him there, holding the angel, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: The angel was jumping all over the place.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he told me to say, zzzz.
[SPEAKER_01]: The angel would settle down.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I did that, and Angel settled down.
[SPEAKER_01]: I flashed the Cuban, and Angel leaped for me, nearly reached me, but he's had a good grip on the harling, on the leash, so he pulled me back.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was very proud of his induction in Alabama, Sports Hall of Fame last year, or the year before, where he was up in Tuscaloosa, along with Joe Sewell, and one or two others, and he has the plaque for that.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, with that...